macmillan.com 2009-04-26

# Macmillan :: Privacy Notice

**us.macmillan.com**

**Privacy Notice**

Effective Date:  April 1, 2008

We at Macmillan (“we” or “Macmillan”) respect your concerns about privacy and value the relationship we have with you.  This Privacy Notice describes the types of personal information we collect on [www.us.macmillan.com](http://www.us.macmillan.com/), how we may use that information, and with whom we may share it.   This Privacy Notice also describes the measures we take to protect the security of the information.  In addition, we describe the choices you can make about how we use the personal information you provide to us, how you can update your contact information, contact us with general questions or comments, inquire about our company and its products and services, or ask any questions you may have about our privacy practices or this website. 

    * _[Ordering our Products](http://us.macmillan.com/splash/policy.html#B)_
    * __Chat Rooms, Forums and Discussion Groups__

**_Information We Collect:_**

**Getting our Newsletters and other information**

**You may sign up to receive our newsletters and/or other information about new releases, author appearances, and special offers.   In order to fulfill your requests, we will ask you for your name and email address, and sometimes certain other information.  You may unsubscribe to our newsletters and alerts at anytime by clicking on the unsubscribe link included on all of our emails to you. **

**Ordering our Products**

When you order from us, we collect your name, billing address, shipping address, email address, phone number, and credit card number. We also gather information on the person who will receive any gift you send (e.g., that person's name and address) and we will retain a record of your purchases. ****

**Surveys and Questionnaires**

**We may ask visitors to our website to complete online surveys and opinion polls on a variety of topics, including their activities, attitudes, and interests as they relate to our products and services.   When you complete a survey we usually collect your name, address, and email address.  We may also ask you for additional information, such as your age, interests, product preferences or zip code.**

**Sweepstakes, Contests and Promotions**

**From time to time we may run sweepstakes, contests or other promotions online.   When you enter a sweepstakes or contest on line, we usually collect your name, address, email address and phone number.  We may also ask you for additional information, such as your age, interests, product preferences or zip code.**

_**Chat Rooms, Forums, and Discussion Groups**_

We may choose to host chat rooms, forums and/or discussion groups on our website. If you choose to participate in a chat room, forum or discussion group, we may request certain information such as your email address and date of birth. Please be aware that some or all information you provide (including personally-identifiable information) in connection with a chat room, forum or discussion group may become publicly available. We reserve the right, at our sole discretion, to save and archive any content of any nature posted to this website and we may (in addition to any other rights we may have to use such content pursuant to the Terms of Use governing your use of this website): 1) disclose such content if required to do so by law or to comply with legal processes; 2) to respond to claims that any of the content violates the property, privacy, publicity or other rights of others; or 3) to protect the rights, property or safety of this website, Macmillan, its employees, users or members of the public.

The blogs and forums to which you are provided access through this website are owned and operated by third-party companies. Use of these sites, as well as such companies' use of any information you may submit on these sites, may be subject to the terms of use and privacy notices applicable to these sites, which we strongly suggest you review. These sites are not owned by Macmillan and are not under our control. 

_**“Contact Us”**_ __  
 You may choose to contact us through our website. If you e-mail us comments or questions, we will have your e-mail address, as well as any other information you choose to provide. 

_**Passive Collection of Information**_

When you visit our website, your browser automatically sends us certain Internet-related information, such as the Internet Protocol (IP) address of the computer you’re using and your originating domain. We also collect certain information about our website visitors, such as how many users visited our site, the average time spent on the site, the pages viewed, and referring websites. By collecting this information, we learn how to best tailor our website to our visitors. While we generally examine such information only in the aggregate, such information could be linked back to individual IP addresses. 

We use cookies on this website.  A cookie is a small piece of information sent by a Web site that is saved on your hard disk by your computer's browser. It holds information a site may need to interact with you and personalize your experience. At us.macmillan.com, we use two kinds of cookies: session cookies and persistent cookies. 

Session cookies exist only for as long as your browser remains open. Once you exit your browser, they go away. Persistent cookies, in contrast, last from visit to visit; they do not go away when you exit your browser.

We use cookies to administer certain functions, and to help you navigate the website more efficiently.  For example, we use session cookies to maintain information we need to have in order for you to shop at us.macmillan.com.  Without the session ID cookie, you can't add merchandise to your bag and carry it to Checkout.

You can use our site without accepting cookies. The "help" portion of the toolbar on most browsers will tell you how to stop accepting new cookies, how to be notified when you receive a new cookie, and how to disable existing cookies.  Remember, though, if you disable all cookies, you may not be able to take advantage of all features of this website.

Collection of site usage information on our site is performed on our behalf by a third party service provider.   In addition to cookies, the service provider may use web beacons to notify the service provider of web page access by visitors.   Our third party service provider may retain such usage information for its own internal purposes. ****

**_How We Use Information We Collect_**

Information collected through our website is used in connection with the purpose for which it was submitted, including:  to contact you to answer a question, to send you a newsletter or other information you have requested, or to enter you into a sweepstakes.  In addition if you purchase a product on our website, we will use information to process that purchase and the related payment. 

We may also use the information we collect to send you information or products we think may be of interest to you, to customize our contacts with you and to do other internal analyses, such as market research, that will allow us to better meet the needs of our customers. We may also use information to enhance your online experience while using our website or to improve the content of the site or to improve the quality or variety of the products and services we offer. ****

**_How We Share Information_**

We may share the information you provide with companies that are related to Macmillan through common ownership. **__**

In addition, we may share information about you with non-affiliated third parties whose products or services may be of interest to you. These third parties may contact you about their products and services. We will not share your information with these third parties for their own marketing purposes if you request that we not do so. We may, however, engage in joint marketing activities with selected third parties and may share personal information about our website visitors with them. 

We also share information provided by our website visitors with service providers we have retained to perform services on our behalf.  For example: when you make a purchase, we may share information about you and your transaction with other companies for the purpose of processing your transaction, and we may retain outside companies to manage databases of customer information and to distribute e-mail offerings. 

In addition, we may disclose information about you (i) if we are required to do so by law, (ii) in response to legal process,  iii) to law enforcement authorities or other government officials, or (iv) when we believe disclosure is necessary or appropriate to prevent physical harm or financial loss or in connection with an investigation of suspected or actual illegal activity. 

We reserve the right to transfer any information we have about you in the event we sell or transfer all or a portion of our business or assets. Should such a sale or transfer occur, we will use reasonable efforts to try to ensure that the transferee uses personal information you have provided through this website in a manner that is consistent with this Privacy Notice.

**_Links to Other Websites_**

We provide links to other websites for your convenience and information, including websites of other companies related to Macmillan through common ownership. These sites may operate independently from www.us.macmillan.com, and may not be under our control. These sites may have their own privacy notices in place, which we strongly suggest you review if you visit any linked website. We may not be responsible for the content of these sites, any products or services that may be offered through these sites, or the privacy practices of these sites.

To try and bring you offers that are of interest to you, we have relationships with other companies that we allow to place ads and provide other services on our Web pages. As a result of your visit to our site, these ad servers and other entities may collect information such as your domain type, your IP address and click-stream information. We are not responsible for the data collection practices of any sites linked to Macmillan nor does our linking to third party websites or services constitute sponsorship or endorsement of the content or business practices on these sites. By use of this Site, you have agreed that you will use the hyperlinks to third party sites at your own risk.

**_Children’s Privacy_**

We do not knowingly collect information from children under 13.   We use technical measures to prevent collection of information from children under 13.    

If our policy concerning collection of information from children under 13 changes, we will revise this portion of the us.macmillan.com privacy notice and will comply with the requirements of the Children's Online Privacy Protection Act.

**_Security_** _  
_ us.macmillan.com is committed to protecting the security of information collected on our site.  We use technical, physical and administrative methods to safeguard and secure the information we collect on line.  When you submit information for a credit card transaction through our purchase pages, we use Secure Sockets Layer (SSL) software to encrypt the information during transmission (however, we do not use a secure connection for other types of activities). 

In connection with your purchases at Macmillan, we use a third party service provider to collect your credit card [or debit card] number (and related information). The third party payment service provider will be solely responsible for the collection, use, and storage of your credit card [or debit card] information. 

Please remember that no data transmission over the Internet, or by other means, can be guaranteed to be 100% secure. Thus, while we strive to protect the information you provide through this website, Macmillan cannot ensure or warrant the security of any information you transmit to us. Therefore, you understand, acknowledge, and agree that you transmit information over this Site at your own risk. 

**_Your Choices_** _  
_ We give you the option of requesting that we not share personal information about you with third parties that are unrelated by common ownership with Macmillan for marketing use. [Click here](mailto:internetmarketing@macmillanusa.com) to send us an e-mail with your name and e-mail address(es) if you DO NOT want us to share your personal information with unrelated third parties for their own marketing use.

We also give you the option of requesting that we not share your information with companies related to Macmillan by common ownership for marketing use. However, PLEASE NOTE that, because of the integrated nature of Macmillan and some of these companies, if you opt out of sharing with them, you will also automatically be opted out of marketing use by Macmillan. That means that you will not receive marketing information from us about books, promotions and services. [Click here](mailto:internetmarketing@macmillanusa.com) to send us an e-mail with your name and e-mail address(es), if you do not want us to share your information with related companies for marketing use (or use the information for marketing purposes ourselves). (Keep in mind, however, that some of our related companies may have independently obtained your information, in which case you may continue to receive communications from those companies, unless you opt out directly with them.)

Please be aware that we are able to effectuate an opt-out only for a specific e-mail address.  So, if you have more than one e-mail address or if you have changed your email address, your opt-out request may not be effectuated properly. If you believe you have opted out, but continue to receive e-mails from us, please contact us by one of the means listed under “How to Contact Us”, below, and we will endeavor to resolve the  issue.

You can "opt-out" of receiving newsletters, advertising and promotional e-mail from us by following the opt-out instructions in our e-mail messages. To ensure that your opt-out request is honored, you must use the designated method in the e-mail message to notify us of your opt-out request, as we cannot guarantee that other methods of notification will be effective or timely.

Please note that even if you choose to opt-out of receiving Macmillan's marketing, we will continue to send you important service related communications, including follow-up messages regarding sweepstakes or contests you have entered or other transactions you have undertaken (e.g., order confirmation). ****

**Macmillan Accounts**

If you would like to review the Personal Information that we have collected from you online in connection with your purchases from Macmillan, log back into your user account. Click on "My Account" to review or make changes to your purchase information at any time. If you are not signed in, you will be prompted to do so. If you do not remember your password, click on the "Forgot your password" link, provide your e-mail address and we will send you your password via e-mail. 

**_Updates to this Privacy Notice_** __

By using this website, you signify your agreement to this Privacy Notice. This Privacy Notice may change from time to time. Changes to this Privacy Notice will become effective when those changes are posted to the Site. Your continued use of the services and the sites subsequent to any changes to this Privacy Policy constitutes your acceptance of the changes. Please review this statement periodically to ensure you are aware of any changes or updates to this Notice.  We indicate the effective date of this Notice (and any updates) at the top of the Notice.

**_How to Contact Us_**

If you would like to update your contact information, [click here](mailto:webmaster@macmillanusa.com).   
If you have any questions about our information practices or our products or services, please contact us by: 

 • [clicking here](mailto:webmaster@macmillanusa.com)  
 • writing us at: 

Macmillan Publishers  
Internet Marketing Department  
175 Fifth Avenue  
New York, NY 10010  
Attention: Internet Marketing Coordinator
